Contact

dmilinovichiii@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dmilinovich (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Node.js

React

MongoDB

Honors-Awards 2019 SVIC People's Choice Award (1st)

Dimitrie Milinovich

Software Engineer Specializing In Full Stack Development and Machine Learning

San Jose, California, United States

Summary

I'm a passionate Software Engineer who's been bringing products to market for over a decade. One of my greatest strengths has always been my desire to learn about anything and everything related to technology. As a result, I've become knowledgeable about a wide array of topics in computing. I've found that this equips me to find solutions others might miss. Some of my most unique projects include:

- Building a grandmaster level Chess AI that learning using Convolutional Neural Networks and a variant on the Monte Carlo Tree Search algorithm
- Building a "Map of the Internet" by mapping geolocations of tens of thousands of random IP addresses
- Creating a GPU watchdog for a cryptocurrency mining rig to reset crashed cards and maximize uptime

I'm always open to discussing interesting projects and unique ideas!

Experience

BetterHelp.com
Full Stack Developer
May 2020 - Present (3 years 4 months)
San Jose, California, United States

- Full stack development using PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, and Twig
- Built APIs and utilized them to render data for new front end counselor and client features
- Designed GoogleAds automated ad deployment system for BetterHelp counselors
- Created a new payments system with Stripe to automate counselor payment verification and issuance

- Discovered optimization issues with the existing matching system and created an improved alternative
- Onboarded new employees, walked them through our systems, and set up their dev environments

gig

Full Stack Engineer

January 2019 - March 2020 (1 year 3 months)

San Jose, California

- Styled and planned the UX and UI for the mobile app and landing page
- Worked with a fast paced focused team in an Agile software environment
- Leveraged a CI / CD pipeline to streamline production
- Designed robust functionality for the back-end admin dashboard
- Integrated Google Firebase and Facebook Analytics for deep integration with their ad networks
- Set up AWS user management with Cognito platform

https://trygig.app

Ambii Inc.

Software Engineer

January 2018 - December 2018 (1 year)

San Jose, California, United States

- Managed Ambii's data harvesting
- Collected large scale datasets from GraceNote's API
- Developed algorithms to associate tracks with businesses' sales
- Created internal APIs for front end team to utilize
- Built a dashboard for at-a-glance understanding of Ambii's market performance

https://ambii.io

Tiltseeker

Founder

March 2017 - December 2017 (10 months)

San Jose, California

- Designed, developed, published, and actively maintain a player assist website for League of Legends used by over 18 thousand gamers
- Built using React, Express, MongoDB, CSS, jQuery, Webpack, Redux, Redis, Bootstrap, React Router, etc.

- Programmed a RESTful API endpoint capable of handling requests at scale
- Designed a server capable of pulling large scale datasets from the Riot API
- Created automation system to generate useful conclusions from big data datasets
- Built a machine learning system using deep neural networks to predict match outcomes in Python

https://tiltseeker.com/

Self-employed Freelance Web Developer January 2014 - August 2016 (2 years 8 months) United States

- -Used Wordpress to create mobile responsive shopping websites for clients.
- -Redesigned past client's sites into React
- -Mastered state management libraries such as Redux
- -Used JavaScript to build upon the CMS in order to create customized functionality such as animations, plugins, and styling to make the user experience smoother

Education

San Jose State University
Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering · (2014 - 2019)